# Tim Carlock

# Web Developer and UX Enthusiast



**1** 314.719.9051

300 3rd St, Apt 605 San Francisco, CA 94107



http://github.com/tcarlock

http://linkedin.com/in/tscarlock



#### Overview

I have over ten years of software strategy, design and development experience, with a particular interest in development methodologies, product design and user experience. I have management and product leadership experience, and I've worked in several industries including financial services, consumer tech and business software. I also co-founded a software startup where I managed product strategy and development.

# **Experience**

#### Web Engineer // Learnist // San Francisco, CA

Feb 2013 - Present

I work on the web team as a full-stack engineer where I'm responsible for the design and development of new features. I work primarily with Ruby on Rails and AngularJS, as well other technologies including CSS3, Sass, CoffeeScript, Redis and Rspec.

- Researched, selected and implemented a split-testing tool (Optimizely) for the web platform, and developed AngularJS service wrappers around the Optimizely HTTP API.
- Rebuilt the email-preference-management system including a redesign of the data-storage architecture, server-side permission checking and the UI for preference management.
- Redesigned and refactored key front-end components including tag clouds, comments and user/board statistics.
- Redesigned the UI and workflow for the content-curation process and created proposed UI redesigns for the primary application views.
- Designed, implemented and monitored a new product experience whereby users subscribe to a board and are provided a daily digest of content. Additional work was done to support feature parity on our mobile clients.

#### Software Engineer // Expedia // San Francisco, CA

May 2012 - Feb 2013

I worked on the social team where I helped develop a hotel-reviews API using Java, Spring and MongoDB.

- Developed an API to serve localized hotel reviews for multiple Expedia sites including hotel search and travel packages. The API was developed using Java/Spring and MongoDB and it was deployed to EC2 with Yammer Metrics for instrumentation.
- Helped manage deployment and provisioning using Jenkins, Capistrano and Chef.
- Participated in daily standups, as well as bi-weekly sprint planning and retrospectives.

#### Co-Founder & Product Lead // Nexly // San Francisco, CA

August 2009 - April 2012

Nexly was a lead-generation and tracking toolset for business-services companies. I was responsible for product strategy, design and development.

- Developed the application using Rails and PostgreSQL running on Heroku. Other technologies included CSS3, jQuery, CoffeeScript, Sass and HAML.
- Developed integration with various social APIs including Facebook, Twitter and LinkedIn.
- Worked closely with users to understand key problems and needs, identify features and develop a product roadmap.
- Hired and managed contract designers and developers and oversaw all aspects of feature development, deployment and review.

### IT Manager - Software Products // Hammond Associates // St. Louis, MO

May 2004 - August 2009

I built and managed a team that was responsible for developing portfolio-management and data-analysis applications for both internal and external use.

- Managed the company's overarching software strategy and supervised up to six direct reports including user-support analysts, a project manager and application engineers.
- Worked with department directors to identify new projects, develop project roadmaps, and present budget proposals to senior management.
- Oversaw the design and development of various applications including data warehousing, portfolio-analysis and management and client reporting.

#### Education

University of Missouri - St Louis // Bachelor of Science - IS

August 2004

• 3.91 Cumulative G.P.A.

University of Missouri - St Louis // Bachelor of Science - Finance

January 2003

- Student of the Pierre Laclede Honors College.
- President of the Delta Sigma Pi Business Fraternity.

## **Skills**

Operating Systems: OS X, Linux (Ubuntu), Windows

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript/CoffeeScript, HTML/HAML, CSS/Sass, Java, C#, SQL

Data Stores: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, MongoDB

Frameworks/Libraries: Rails, ¡Query, AngularJS, BackboneJS, Bootstrap

Gems: Rspec, Devise, CanCan, FactoryGirl, Paperclip, Thinking Sphinx, Omniauth, Sunspot, Koala, RABL, jbuilder

Dev/Design Tools: Pivotal Tracker, RVM, Git, Github, Jenkins, Sublime Text, Illustrator, Photoshop, easel.io, Balsamiq